I heard that
you also got into a university in Bangkok.
I got accepted to the Faculty of Sports Science
through the athlete quota.
Are you okay
with me going to study in Bangkok?
Of course.
I forgot that we couldn’t ride a bike
and play around forever.
No matter where we are,
we will never be apart.
I promise.
Class, attention.
Thank you.
The class is over.
Let’s go have ice cream.
Sure.
Shall we go ride a bike at Koh Loi?
Ko.
Ko, wake up.
Ko!
(I have this dream again.)
(I dreamed about my old days,
places, and people from my past)
(as if we had never grown up.)
(But the reality is we are growing up every day.)
(I’m well aware of that.)
(I also know that I’m not a high school kid anymore.)
(Bangkok scent, I can’t explain it in words.)
(But it’s certainly not
the ocean scent of my hometown.)
(The only thing that has not changed
is the man by my side.)
Can I have some too?
I already made one for you. It’s over there.
You really read my mind.
When are you leaving?
I was supposed to leave half an hour ago.
What?
Why are you still here?
You didn’t wake me up.
This is your fault.
So this is my fault?
I don’t want to go.
I want to hold you a bit longer.
Don’t be a baby, doctor.
If your patients saw you like this,
they would be upset.
Let them be.
I still want to hold my boyfriend.
Okay, I’m going to get ready.
I’m going.
(What’s up? Why are we having a group call?)
(My mom wants to know
who will come home for the New Year.)
(She needs to know the number to tell the caterer.)
(I’m going.)
(I already told Augar
that I will arrive a day before Achi.)
(What about you, Ko? Will you go home?)
(If you are going, I will clear out my car
and free up some space.)
Ko, Augar and August ask
if you’re going home for the New Year?
I have to check first.
I’ll tell you later.
I’ve got to go.
See you.
He has to check first.
Will he go?
(Why are you riding home with me?)
(If I had another choice, I wouldn’t ride with you.)
(I’ve never asked you to do it.)
(Why did you take Dad’s car?)
(If you ask me what hasn’t changed,)
(I’m a better driver than you.)
(I would say these guys.)
(August is busy with his capstone project.)
Professor.
I’m not sure about…
(Augar is a rising star of his team.)
(Achi, who attends a university away from us,
is busy with his research project.)
(My life right now?)
(Good looks are not a free pass.)
(I earn extra money from modeling.)
(But I’m still attending classes.)
From the latest case that I show you…
(Ko Song is now doing his ward rotations.)
(Now, there’s only a river between us.)
(I don’t get why I was so worried back then.)
[I arrived at school.]
[Tell me what you want to have for dinner.
I’ll buy it for you.]
Ko.
Why did you come to school so early?
My boyfriend has a morning class.
So I woke up with him.
Your boyfriend is a med student, right?
So he is studying at a hospital,
just like in the movies, right?
Yes, something like that.
How long have you been dating?
He must be busy with school.
It’s unlikely that he met you in college.
We’ve been dating since high school.
He was my next-door neighbor.
Damn, that sounds so romantic.
Don’t tell me that one of you has a tree
and the leaves fall into the other house.
Seriously, Ko?
That sounds like a movie script.
It’s true.
When I go home,
I’ll take a picture of the tree and show you.
Good. I want to see it.
When will you go home?
This New Year holiday?
Yes.
That’s why I can’t go to the countdown party
with you guys.
It’s okay.
You can come with us next year.
You should go home.
Are you going with your boyfriend?
I’m not sure.
You came home on time today,
exactly at 8 p.m.
I’m exhausted.
Are you hungry?
Yes.
I’m hungry, but also tired.
Can you feed me through a tube, honey?
Stop joking around.
Did you hit me over the tube feeding joke
or me calling you honey?
Of course, the latter.
Why are you calling me honey?
Why are you still feeling shy?
Everyone calls their loved one "honey".
But it’s weird.
It sounds cringey.
Okay, okay.
I’ll stop teasing you.
I won’t call you honey.
I’ll call you Orange. It’s much cuter.
That’s not bad.
Orange.
What?
Orange is cute.
What are you doing?
Are you bored?
I barely have time to be with you.
I get it. I’m not bored.
Don’t get bored with me.
Sure.
Will you go home this New Year?
I haven’t checked my schedule yet.
I’ll tell you tomorrow.
AROI
What’s wrong?
You are the one who told us
to meet at this restaurant.
But you don’t eat anything.
That’s right.
You make me lose my appetite.
I’m not hungry.
I just want to meet you.
Okay. Then I’ll go back to eating.
How can you eat?
Look at your friend.
He’s stressed about something.
What else can he be stressed about?
It’s always about Ko Song.
Is that true?
Okay, it’s obvious.
What’s wrong?
What are you fighting about this time?
He and I barely fight.
But that’s the reason why I’m feeling this way.
Why?
Because you don’t fight?
Yes.
Everything he says sounds reasonable.
I try to understand him.
He said he is busy.
When he gets home and falls asleep
without spending time with me.
I understand him.
But I secretly feel upset about it.
Are you and Achi fighting, Augar?
No.
Really?
No question!
Look.
Damn.
Let me see.
Is this chat between a couple or a thesis?
Stop it, jerk.
We are fighting every day.
It’s either he’s mad at me, or I’m mad at him.
Because we are apart,
we always have something to fight about.
Then what do you do?
What can I do?
There’s nothing I can do.
So you just live like this?
Yeah.
So how are you going to go home?
Have you talked to him?
If you want to ride home with me,
I’ll clean out my car.
He said he will let me know today.
I’ll bet 100 baht. He’s not going.
Me too.
You guys are such jerks.
Why are you barely eating?
What’s wrong?
I had dinner with Augar and August earlier.
Where?
Samyan?
Yes.
I was going to ask you to join us.
But I thought most of the restaurants
would be closed by the time you arrived.
Augar can’t eat dinner late.
Otherwise, he will be scolded by his coach.
It’s okay.
We can find time to meet up with them again.
How about the New Year?
We can meet them if we go home.
Right, I was going to tell you.
I can’t go home with you this New Year.
I have to stay to help my professor.
I may have to work the night shift
on New Year's Eve.
Work the night shift?
You will be tired.
You should eat a lot to gain energy.
So you will have energy to study.
Eat this. It’s delicious.
Did you take out the trash?
Yes.
I also threw away the postal boxes.
Well done.
Of course.
Orange.
What?
You understand me, right?
Yeah.
Do you really mean it?
If you are not okay with it,
I’ll talk to my professor.
It’s okay.
If you swap your shift,
you will have to do an extra shift later.
It will be tiring to travel to see my parents.
If you have to work after you get back,
you will be tired.
Okay.
Let’s go to sleep.
It’s really delicious.
I want to try it. Is this a new restaurant?
You need to try it. It’s a secret place.
Augar. Achi.
Hello.
You bail on us again, Ko Song.
Yeah.
I’m really busy.
Sorry. I’ll take a rain check.
If you bail on us again, I won’t let it slide.
Come on, get in the car.
See you.
Good luck with work.
You’d better drive carefully.
Got it.
See you.
Can you put it away, Achi?
I’m changing lanes.
Can you hold it still? I can’t take a bite.
Can you hold it yourself?
Then my hand will get oily.
If my hand slips from the wheel,
we could be in trouble.
When the road was clear,
why didn’t you eat then?
You kept talking.
How hard could it be
to hold the skewer for me?
I’m afraid that it might poke into your eye.
Why would it poke into my eye?
I don’t use my eyes to eat it.
What if you suddenly make a turn
or hit the brake?
Why do I have to explain everything?
So you are sick of explaining things to me?
What’s wrong with you?
I’m sick of arguing about the same thing.
Yeah, the restaurant thing too.
[Don’t forget to eat something before you leave.]
[You didn’t get much sleep last night.
You could feel lightheaded.]
[I’m not sure if it’s edible.]
[I made it last night
when you were nagging me about my slow packing.]
I’m going to turn down the air conditioner.
Are you hot?
Sure. I’ll be fine.
Can you get the blanket at the back
and give it to Achi?
He probably feels cold.
I do this because you are here.
Normally, I would turn off the air conditioner.
Don’t you feel hot?
Of course, but Achi gets cold easily.
What else can I do?
It’s not that hot
when I turn off the air conditioner.
You guys are really fighting all the time.
I thought you were kidding.
This is how much we argue
when we’re together.
It’s worse when we are apart.
Aren’t you sick of fighting with him?
No.
It’s better than having no one to fight with.
It’s because we really want to be together.
You’ve grown up a lot, Augar.
Because I’ve grown up,
I understand these kinds of things.
Achi, move the seat for me.
Wait a sec.
Thanks for the ride, Augar.
Yeah.
Tell August to return my comic book.
You really hold a grudge about this.
See you later.
Did you bring your swimming suit?
Of course.
You should go.
See you.
Drive safe, Augar.
Ko.
Mom.
I thought you would arrive in the evening.
I haven’t prepared a meal for you.
Augar gives me a ride.
We left this morning.
Is that so?
Where is Ko Song?
He didn’t come with you?
He has to work today.
That’s too bad.
I thought we all would be together.
It’s okay.
Let’s go inside.
Sure.
My son is a big boy now.
You’re clinging to me like a monkey.
(Back then we had only this silly phone.)
(But it was much easier to talk to him.)
Hey!
Let’s go out to eat. I’m hungry.
(I’m afraid to call you as often as I used to.)
(Because I don’t want to bother you at work.)
[SEND A MESSAGE]
[I arrived home. Have a great day at work.
Don’t skip your meal.]
(The scent of my house makes me feel so good.)
(No matter who I’m trying to be this year,)
(when I’m home,
the old me is slowly coming back.)
Ko.
(But something has never changed.)
(At least, my mom has never changed.)
Ko.
Can you go to the market with me?
Why don’t you go with Dad?
I want to stay home.
She wants to show you off to everyone.
Me? Why do you want to show me off?
My son is handsome and smart.
You also come to visit me
during the New Year holiday.
Of course, I want to show you off.
You want to show me off
because I came home?
Yes.
You came home.
It means you think I’m important to you.
In simple words,
who you choose to spend the New Year with,
it means that person is important to you.
That’s why I want you to come home
for the holiday every year.
Alright, let’s go.
He agrees to go with me.
We will be right back, Tiam.
Ko, don’t forget to go greet the uncle.
Sure.
SRIRACHA MUNICIPAL MARKET
Mom, can we go home now?
No.
Hello, Sri.
This is Ko. Do you remember him?
He’s my son.
Hello.
It’s been a while since I last saw you.
Is this your son?
Yes.
Hello.
Who is this?
This is Ko, my son.
Mom, let’s go home. Stop showing me off.
Wait a sec.
Right.
What?
Can you go buy this for me?
Buy the things on the list.
Okay, okay.
If we split up to shop,
we can finish shopping faster.
Don’t you say you want to go home?
I’ll buy fish.
PORK AND OFFAL PORRIDGE,
BLOOD PIG SOUP
Hey, Ko.
Hello, Uncle.
Are you okay? You are coughing.
I was wondering
if you guys would come home this year.
I saw August this morning.
He said you guys would arrive today.
Achi arrived in Bangkok yesterday.
So Augar drove home today.
How are you doing, Uncle?
Are you okay?
Same as usual.
I’m getting older every day.
What are you doing here today?
Did your mom ask you
to buy groceries again?
Yes.
Here, Uncle.
What is it?
The list of my grocery order.
Though you are all grown up,
your mom still asks you
to buy soy sauce for her.
Go see me at my shop.
Okay, Uncle.
I’ll go there when I finish eating this.
Ko.
When is your commencement ceremony?
You need to tell me in advance.
I need to rent a van.
It’s several months away.
I haven’t graduated yet.
It’s not that far away.
It’s only a few months.
Watch out. It’s spilling.
I’m so excited.
I’m excited too.
I’m proud of you.
Who is calling?
Hello. What’s up, August?
(What else could it be, Boss Ko?)
Hurry up and come here.
We’ve been waiting for you.
Augar and Achi make me feel like
a third wheel on the beach.
Damn.
(I’m helping my mom in the kitchen.)
You are not cool.
Why don’t you come
and help my mom clean the vegetables?
Then I’ll go to see Augar.
(Why would I do that?
It’s not my mom’s vegetables.)
Ko, you should go meet your friends.
I’ll help your mom here.
(See? Your dad even tells you
to come to hang out with me.)
(Hurry up. Don’t forget
to bring your swimming suit, asshole.)
Asshole.
Ko, you should go meet your friends.
We will have the New Year dinner together anyway.
Right.
Okay.
I’ll go meet my friends.
I’ll be back when it’s getting dark.
Alright.
Go. I’ll do it myself.
Bye.
I’m doing it. I’m not slacking off.
Hey.
Are you Ko?
Yes, it’s me.
I’m a relative of the former owner of this house.
I moved here two years ago.
I went to visit my relative in another province.
So we didn’t meet last time.
You’re Ko’s relative?
Yes.
His dad wanted to sell this house.
But Ko asked him not to do that.
He liked this house.
I have to travel a lot.
So I don’t have time to water the trees.
I’m lucky that your parents help take care of them.
Otherwise, they would have been dead.
Ko really likes the orange tree.
He asked me to take good care of it.
I like it too.
When I was young, I always picked oranges
from the tree to eat.
If it bears fruit, I’ll pick and give them to you.
I’ve got to go.
Don’t forget to say hi to him for me.
Say hi to who?
♪ Will say "I love you" ♪
♪ Will say "I love you" so you know ♪
♪ No more watching from afar, letting chances go ♪
♪ To make this worth the wait after all ♪
Argh!
Stop it.
You are late.
Why don’t you join them?
No, I don’t want to get wet.
How did you end up coming?
Didn’t you say you had to work?
Yes, I had to work, but I found a way.
What’s going on with you two?
You are living together.
But you two look really worried.
I’m not sure if I made a mistake choosing a med school.
I feel like I always leave him alone.
What makes you think that?
I always ask him if he’s okay.
He always says he’s okay.
But I don’t know if he means what he says
or if he said that so I won’t be worried.
I wanted to ask him that,
but I was afraid that we would end up fighting.
Your problem is that you don’t say what is on your mind.
That’s why you keep worrying about things.
If I were living with Achi,
I would do everything
to make our relationship as good as it can be
Trust me.
It’s not that hard to talk to him.
Compared to being apart.
Damn.
Longing is like a double-edged sword.
I’m so sad that I can’t see Achi.
But I’m glad that it makes me realize…
how much I love him.
To tell you the truth.
I’ve never felt that we are apart.
You two are living together
Don’t let things drift you apart.
Augar.
Ko Neung threw sand into my eye.
Which one?
The right eye.
It’s out.
What are you doing?
Happy New Year.
Here is your food.
Hello.
Damn, this is so cool.
Make yourself at home
I didn’t even know that they prepared this.
What should I do if my mom does this too?
Come on.
The adults want to celebrate.
Don’t think too much about it.
Just let them do whatever they want.
Hello, hello.
Hello.
Everyone, today is a good day to celebrate the New Year.
I also want to celebrate Ko and his friends’ graduation.
No, one of us hasn’t graduated yet.
He has two years left.
That’s right.
He’s a med student.
It’s okay.
Let’s celebrate for him in advance.
Alright.
Ko, come here and sing.
Yeah, both of you.
Come on.
Ko, Ko, Ko.
No, Mom. I don’t want to sing.
I can’t sing.
Come on.
Ko, don’t be shy.
Come on. Get up.
I can’t sing.
Ko, Ko, Ko.
Don’t be shy. Take it.
Ko Song, take it.
Let’s give them a round of applause.
It’s your family’s party.
Do I have to sing?
Yes.
Alright.
If you know the song, please sing along.
Because we can’t sing.
♪ Every time that we meet again ♪
♪ Something grows a little more each day ♪
♪ The closer we are, the more I feel the love I’ve waited for ♪
♪ Might not be too far away at all ♪
♪ Even when winter fades I’ll still wait on ♪
♪ Till the final raindrop falls, hope is never gone ♪
♪ As long as I have you holding my hand as we walk on ♪
♪ I fear nothing if this season has you ♪
What is this?
Easy, or you will tear it.
Here.
You look like Harry Potter.
You look great.
Why are you suddenly complimenting me?
I don’t know.
You just look really good today.
Really?
Why are you suddenly being polite to me?
I just want to do it.
Are you teasing me back?
Let’s make up.
Make up? We are not fighting
It’s okay to fight.
I want you to say what is on your mind.
I can adjust things to accommodate you.
You know that, right?
I feel bad to ask you.
You are tired from studying.
I don’t want to make you even more tired.
There’s nothing more important to me than our relationship.
You know that, right?
I’m not worried if I have to try harder.
I’m more worried about hurting your feelings.
If you want me to come, just tell me.
Don’t wait for me to come.
How can I tell you?
I said it was okay.
If you want me to come, just tell me.
Can’t you swap your shift?
Let’s go together.
You can tell me that.
I can do everything for you.
Then…
Can you come back to the dorm early?
You always come home late.
You immediately fall asleep when you get back.
We barely have a chance to talk these days.
I’m sorry.
I’ll try to manage my schedule better.
I promise.
I’ll talk to you until you’re sick of me, honey.
Honey?
Why can’t I call you that?
You can.
I’m just not used to it.
It’s fine if you want to call me honey.
Hey, Ko.
Why is it always me?
Can’t you act lovey-dovey somewhere else?
Why do I always run into it?
Ko, you look great.
Handsome.
Step closer.
Okay, you look great.
Dad, take their pictures.
Let's take some photos.
Smile.
Come on.
Okay.
One, two, three.
♪ Will say "I love you" ♪
♪ Will say "I love you" so you know ♪
♪ No more watching from afar, letting chances go ♪
♪ To make this worth the wait after all ♪
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Happy New Year.
♪ Distance only makes me think it over ♪
♪ And pray that we will again meet each other ♪
(The scent of Bangkok, the scent of the ocean,
or the scent of my house,)
(The scent of New Year’s Eve, the scent of New Year.)
(Now I’m not worried at all about what I will come my way.)
♪ To make this worth the wait after all ♪
♪ Oh, baby, I love you ♪
(As long as he’s here with me.)
(No matter where we are or what day it is,)
(As long as we are together, that is the best thing already.)
I’m leaving, Dad and Mom.
Yeah.
Bye. Give me a hug.
See you. Bye.
Goodbye.
Goodbye. Drive safe.
Come on.
(Everyone told me change is the scariest thing)
(Changes can take everything away from us.)
(whether it’s love, friendship, fame, or wealth)
Why do you need to raise your voice?
(Changes can lead to a fight.)
(It can make us mad or misunderstand each other.)
I just told you to drive carefully.
Why do you have to be so mad?
I am driving carefully.
(But that’s not all.)
(Now, I see the other side.)
(Changes make us want to be a better person for something…)
(…or for someone.)
(Changes help us grow up.)
(Changes make us realize what our responsibilities are)
(and how to balance them
with our own needs and the needs of others.)
Congratulations, the fresh graduate.
♪ Will say "I love you" ♪
♪ Will say "I love you" so you know ♪
♪ No more watching from afar, letting chances go ♪
♪ To make this worth the wait after all ♪
I love you, Orange.
(The world is moving forward every day.)
(I know that nothing can stay the same.)
I love you too, Ko Song.
(As I already said, as long as I come home and see him,)
(it doesn’t matter where we live;
I won’t be afraid of any changes.)
♪ Will say "I love you" so you know ♪
♪ To make this worth the wait after all ♪
- THE END -
♪ “I love you” I couldn't say ♪
♪ Kept them hidden, scared my heart would break ♪
♪ But once we drifted far away ♪
♪ They kept returning every day ♪
♪ Thinking that's what I should've said ♪
♪ All I can do is keep them inside an old picture ♪
♪ And pray that we will again meet each other ♪
♪ Wanna say "I love you" ♪
♪ Wanna say "I love you" so you know ♪
♪ No more watching from afar, letting chances go ♪
♪ To make this worth the wait after all ♪